option e to the t is to ask what
properties does it have the most
important one and from some binding
property is that it is its own
derivative together with the added
condition that inputting zero returns
one it's actually the only function with
this property and you can illustrate
what this means with a physical model if
e to the T describes your position on a
number line as a function of time then
you start at the number one and what
this equation is saying is that your
velocity the derivative of position is
always equal to that position the
farther away from zero you are the
faster you move so even before knowing
how to compute e to the T exactly going
from a specific time to a specific
position this ability to associate each
position with a velocity paints a very
strong intuitive picture of how the
function must grow you know that you'll
be accelerating and at an accelerating
rate with an all-around feeling of
things getting out of hand quickly
and if you add a constant to that
exponent like e to the 2 times T the
chain rule tells us that the derivative
is now two times itself so at every
point on the number line rather than
attaching a vector corresponding to the
number itself first double the magnitude